Hello, good morning, good evening, good
night. Welcome to another episode of
Exot Talk Show. So, we are going to do
some my coding session. So, you just
going to watch me coding. Okay, I'm
going to use Emacs. Uh, so Emac uh very
technical stuff, Emacs and we're going
to code some JavaScript and Unicode.
Okay, so you can see.
So let me start to show you if you are
watching offline play at 1.5 speed and
if you are here say hi
pop out chat if you are here say hi.
Okay so we going to code so you can see
we're going to write a JavaScript
application so that you can type
something like uh good morning how are
you and it will convert them to this uh
circled letter Uni code. Okay.
uh and so I have already written
something similar like that so let's go
check them out so Latin based characters
uh wait actually so it's not here so let
me show you okay so you go to unic code
search and uh go to let's see uh go down
unic code xardinfo you'll find it just
search for unic code x a my name search
for unic code you'll find it okay so for
example Oh, we have upside down text
like you can type how are you today and
you got this upside down text you can
copy it and for example paste it here.
So go here paste.
So that's upside down text. Fantastic.
Amazing. Okay, that's one of the
application.
Uh you can find it just unic code upside
down text. Search for it. Search my
name. You'll find on my website
kasardi.info.
So let's see if we can
it, you know. Let's see if it will find
my website. Unico upside down text
upside down converter.
Okay. Did they steal my uh did they
steal or
you know some of these websites steal
my website code? But you don't know if
they did it first or I did it first.
Anyway, so did they did my website show
up? There it is. Okay. Exo upside upside
down text. Okay.
Okay. So you can find it. So that's one
application. Then there is more.
Uh, so let's go. So let's magnify this.
Okay. So let's see. Let's go. Go. Okay.
So let's
move this up.
Uh upside down text and
we have convert text to unicore
characters math font. So here you can
good morning. Okay. So you got
franker. This this uh this style of font
is called franker. Okay. And you can
have double stroke, you can have math
bold, you can have math itallic, and you
can have math script. So for example,
let's go to my Twitter and let's show
them stuff. Twitter.
Good morning. So uh paste I mean there
it is. Twitter,
you see? So, now let's go to Frankfurt.
Copy and reply
Frank. So, there it is. Good morning.
And let's go back to the previous uh
up down upside down. Good morning.
Copy that. Go to Twitter.
Reply. Good morning. Upside down.
Fantastic.
Okay. Then you can then you have squared
letter. Okay. So, select all. Good
morning. Fantastic. Just copy that. Copy
to data. Paste it. Re reply. Paste.
Do it.
There it is. Fantastic. End. So that's
squared letters of Unicode. Then there's
more. Let's go to um
full width characters.
So you type good morning.
Copy
full width demonstrate.
Okay. Each one of these are one single
character. No space. For example,
pasting Emacs. So you can see each one
of these is a single character unicore
character. There's no space between
them. These are called full width
characters. They came from
uh they came from Chinese basically
because when you type Chinese, the
Chinese characters are aligned. Each
character, you know, is a square. But
then if you have English, they misalign
the text. Therefore,
uh, back then 20 20 30 years ago, they
created full width English letters. So,
each one of these English letters is
full square. So, so that when you use
them in Chinese font, they create like
they don't misalign the text. Okay,
that's the that's origin of this full
width. So they also happen in Japanese,
in Korean or Vietnamese, basically the
Asian languages. Uh but today they are
out of fashion because when you when you
write English in full width then it it's
kind of ugly. Okay. uh so so in so they
rather you know so many of depend
depending on the Chinese font some of
them
they use full width English some of them
don't okay so for example uh let's go to
font um
uh let me show you a Chinese uh font
page okay so you todo CSS not to-do you
go to visual CSS says search on my
website kasi visual CSS you'll find it
you got go down there's all kind of
fonts so there's Chinese font guide so I
give you a guide on Chinese font so well
typically Chinese font uh you have also
sans serif and serif although I mean so
that it's analogous to the to the
English sans serif and serif but
so it's analogous okay because Chinese
is entirely different uh character set
but it's s but the idea is similar. So
you have sans serif where every stroke
is even uniform. There's no decorative
serif. Okay, sans serif which is most
widely used. [snorts] Then you also do
have serif font. So you have little like
wedges uh at the end of a stroke. So you
got serif, sans serif and serif. But you
also have bush style bush style. In bush
sty st st st st st st st st st st st st
st st st st st st st st st st st st st
st style the width of the stroke varies
as if you are using a brush pen okay so
you got bush style anyway so that's a
basic introduction to Chinese font
uh and you know so you can look at
Chinese font on the on windows that's
bundled with every Microsoft Windows
these are Chinese font okay so you got
several you got sim you got you got
Microsoft yeah you got Microsoft
uh H uh J Hi. Okay. Then you got Simhi.
Okay. That's a kind of standard
Microsoft ones and more and fan. Okay.
And on Apple on the Mac, you also have
several um [clears throat] standard, you
know, bundled with every Mac, Chinese
phone, ping fan, uh pinfan, and uh so
these are sans serif and you got serifi.
Okay. Then you got uh then you got um
you got several other variations. Then
you got um
yeah you got the um kite which is
variable strokes width. [snorts]
Okay. So that's like basic introduction
to Chinese font. So let's copy that.
Go to today's talk show. Show show in
browser. We're going to add it here. So
because that's the things we talked
about uh paste a link here make a link
make a list show in browser
there okay and we demonstrated these um
many of these applications so let's copy
let's put the links here so open them
search for topic at the bottom so if you
are here say hi okay I'm going to read a
comment in a moment okay so uh so let's
based characters convert text to unic
characters. Press a key to extract all
URLs in this text block. Okay, we did.
Close it. Okay, then go here. Paste it.
Link linkify demo. Make a make a list
show in browser. Back to Emacs. Switch
the window. So you can see all the
windows, all the commands I call is
shown up there. Okay. Did I? Yeah, the
Okay, so it's this is too big. I need to
adjust it. Okay, now it's better. You
see all the commands we called in the
past is all here.
As I move the cursor, you can can you
see? So if I delete this whole
paragraph, you can see the pink window
says smart delete, you know. So undo.
You see undo and the keystroke on the
left showing browser. That's Kasa fly
keys. It's the most efficient key
binding system in the universe, but it's
for Emacs you uh users. So you can
download it. It's free. It's more
efficient than Vim. Okay. So, here we
demonstrated several of these and we
talked about Chinese font. We and we
talked about full width characters. Now,
let's go back next. Hippiness.
Hippiness.
[snorts] About 30 years ago
uh around 19 uh 1993,
I was working as a secretary. I I touch
type for for uh the salespeople.
Then at noon there's this uh you know at
noon you can go out to buy some food for
lunch. There is this Vietnamese shop
they make uh they make you know some
some Vietnamese sandwich. I forgot but
so you form a line you know. So so but
every time next please. Um,
you know, she says hippiness. Hippiness.
What she meant is that may I help you
next? May I help you next? So, so I just
remember that hippiness.
Okay. How are you today? So, speaking of
So, uh, Sansiza
says, "Hi, speaking of Latin characters,
I've recently discovered input method in
Emacs. Indeed, Latin old postfix input
method has been very helpful in my Latin
study. Fantastic. Yeah, Emacs is the
this all powerful thing. Okay.
Now, have you messed with Haskell
lately?
No, I don't plan to. Well, I tried 15
years ago and I talked about that often
in my live stream. So, but what I am
learning is F. Okay, I hope to really
focus and get my gears, you know, get
get really uh good at F. And the the
other thing I'm learning also kind of
together is the ling lan proof system.
So F is you know they are they are part
of the ML family. Meta language. Meta
language is the first one about about 50
years ago. ML meta lang stand for meta
language ML then you have camel you have
o camel then you have f okay they are
all in the same family
so that's what I want to really get good
at f
um uh and then the ling proof system
okay
so uh oh that's why in non they have
prop type uh Not
full width characters reminds me of
homoglyph attacks. Yes,
that's interesting topic of these all
the spammers and scammers and today all
the [snorts] Bitcoin or or crypto scam,
you know, like all over, you know, on
Twitter like every every half the page
you'll see the the the Twitter scams. So
I mean the the the the bitcoin I mean
the bit not just bitcoin but the you
know crypto and or back then you know
this is like even five years ago 10
years ago like like um the chain you
know blockchain technology oh it's going
to revolution revolutionize
humanity blockchain but and today it's
AI you know this
[snorts] the collapse of USA and zoomers
most you know starting with the
Malaysian these idiots they go to
YouTube because they can make money you
know let's do YouTube you know them
scums [laughter]
and today my Twitter is mostly hot girls
okay
and this is made by AI
>> because I've seen so many of them
[music]
like So many of them every day you can
see the almost exactly that every day.
Well, everyone each one is different.
Okay.
But uh yeah, so we what what we talking
about? Yeah. The scammers, you know.
Okay. So, one of the the the scam
technique is okay, we digressed, shall
we? Yeah, we can. Why not? So, uh so
search for Saudi info search. Okay. Go
to saudi.com. You you'll get this search
box. What we want to search search for
the word scam
software engineering social scams index.
Okay, that's what that's part of the
series of articles. Agile voodoo
diagram. Agile.
these people. You know this quite
interesting agile and and programming
patterns. These scums, they died
with the beginning of the AI era, you
know, because they can no longer sustain
their voodoo.
You know, before AI, like AI is today is
amazing. Okay, it's like you have 10
professors working for you around the
clock as a private tutor
around the clock. Anytime you have a
question about math, about programming,
esoteric questions requiring uh PhD
degree level whatever chemistry or
programming technique technology or
computers or CPU or what [snorts]
or or the history of CPU what whatever
you know you instantaneously you ask AI
and that's even better than some of the
specialized professors.
Okay, that's a the significance most pe
people don't know. They they have no
idea. But you got this
scammers and telling you, wow,
AI is going to be this or that or AGI or
AI ethics on Twitter every
day, you know, like like turns up every
day. Okay. So anyway, AI so so AI. So
one thing we we know quite interesting
by by chance AI killed this this agile
voodoo and lots of similar like
programming patterns that's been going
around for like 20 years programming
patterns. Okay. Anyway, I digressed a
lot. So this is one of my articles. So I
wanted to talk about something else. I
just happened to run into that article.
Okay. Now let's go back. It's no worry.
one by one we'll get to what we are
talking about we can't you know so
there's so many uh got too many articles
to talk about okay but I what I wanted
to tell you uh is about the umh
Google API okay so let's go there okay
so Google am scam 2019 let's go there
and translation SEO scam 2011 so the
page I wanted to go to is this one web
spam scam an SEO index. Okay, open it.
So, but we run into this Google AM scam
2019 Google became extreme evil. Now,
this article is part of the Google
crimes. Okay, so there's about like 20
articles, 30 articles documenting the
Google Google's crime beginning about
2010.
You know, Google was one of the greatest
corporation in humanity doing good and
Google software is the best of them all.
That's the beginning of Google. But
beginning around 2010, they became the
most evil. They became they you know
they got switch you know ba basically
they they became uh deep state. Okay.
Very deep state that Google runs USA
basically.
runs half of USA. You can't be too
anyway. So Google, okay, so there's uh
20 30 articles documenting the crimes of
Google.
Uh so that's uh site talk and what I
wanted to get to is so here's another
article. This is translation SEO scam
happened around 2011,
which is they you know you you got
emails from these nice people. They're
going to ask you, hey, may I translate
one of your article at this or that page
URL? May may we translate it, you know,
very helpful. But the payload is that
they want their website is actually
selling something fishy, you know, you
know, or more or whatever. They are
selling something,
but they want to they want to like get
supposedly get your permission to to
have your article translated and put on
their website. Why they do that? What's
a go what's a I mean what does it good
for them? Well, so that they have a link
to your website. Your website is
reputable. Now you are associated with
that website that W. So it in help them
increase their you know reputation even
though they may be a scam website
whatever. So there's a translation SEO
scam you know they they ask they send
you email very nicely you know request
requesting permission to uh translate
your article. Okay [snorts] so that's
2011. So let's copy that URL back here.
Let's
paste the link here. document what we
have talked about back to the browser
and what we want to go is this index web
spam scam SEO index. Okay, there are
about 30 articles
documenting the scam and scam and spam
phenomenon starting around I guess 2011.
Okay. Well, my experience per my
experience goes way back like it was
starting in 2002. Okay.
Well, my online experience goes back to
1992,
but I only started to document this in
2002. In fact, I haven't, you know, that
means this is just random documentation.
Okay. So, anyway, you got 30 articles
documenting the scams and spams
happening over the past 30 years. the
internet the history of the internet.
Okay. So one of the example you have
seen is that translation scam 2011.
Okay. This this article
this is part of the SEO scam which began
by the Google scum. SEO it stand for uh
search engine optimization.
It's it's it's a it's a um euphemism.
It's a euphemism for Google, the
billiondoll corporation to get you to
help them help help their search engine
effectively. Okay. So they they they
want to get you millions and billion you
know like
you know there are there are eight
billions people on earth. So probably
half of them use the internet therefore
Google. So they want to get like 4
billion people to promote somehow like
promote help their Google's search
engine to make it better. Okay. So they
they Google created this
SEO you know uh search engine
optimization and you idiots the
programming industry you know the idiots
they followed [laughter] well they
followed in part because it for selfish
reasons just like open source you know
SEO oh I can make my website rank higher
oh god I need to learn that you know I
need to do that I need to follow their
rules
So I I rank higher, you know. So Google
set this up. So make all the website
fight for this instead of you know like
naturally
how do you get your product or website
or your writing to rank higher? Of
course you write better. Okay. That's
it. That that is the only rule in entire
human humanity. You just do better your
quality, improve your quality, improve
your knowledge, improve improve your
style, whatever. Okay? Not the SEO
by one corporation that happens in
the year of our Lord 2000. Okay.
But Google scammed the programming
industry idiots with selfish motiv
motivation. Yeah. Well, you you know you
can make your you can make money by
ranking higher. So you you know follow
our techniques. Google Google began
this. Okay. So in fact I have you know
so in fact I have documented that case.
So you go to Google crimes
index and search for SEO.
Okay. So that's one article. Then Google
search ranking ingredients. Okay. So
there article why does Google give SEO
advice 2010
you know it became you know this SEO
became a good thing you know among the
EDR idiot programming industry you know
the web the publishers you know they
think I mean they are the SEO is
perceived like a a good thing you know
but in fact you know so in but in my
opinion it's a it's a it's basically
Google
it's it's a how shall you say you know
it it's a it's you know it's not a good
thing okay it's basically Google making
people to submit to to follow Google's
to make Google search engine better to
to you know so they dominate so they can
slightly control the way things go you
know it's just just for Google okay to
help the Google corporation as opposed
to help others website like Microsoft
search engine or whatever other search
engine you know it's a way to help
Google
that is my opinion okay so that's this
article
okay we digressed far uh and we haven't
get to what I want to do okay so uh but
let me go back to what you just
mentioned which is about the um homogly
attack okay that would be here web span
scam search for Search
H O M O. Uh, no, I didn't find it
because because I was trying to avoid
the academic jargon, homograph.
Okay, but I have it here. So, let's see.
Web spam scam SEO index. Okay. Uh,
Google sitemap.org
domain type squatting scam. Twitter spam
farm 2011.
Uh, Google sitemap or domain typo
squatting scam 2012
by followers scam. Twitter 2012
Daily Mail stealing images 2012. Daily
Mail is a scam like a scum website. They
they they post girls tits and ass and
they steal all over Daily Mail from UK,
United Kingdom. Wikipedia [snorts]
donation scam still ongoing. Massive
money went to uh Jimmy Whale's pocket.
Wikipedia donation scam. And I I donated
back in like 2003, 2004 or so. I donated
$2 when that's when Wikipedia was real
Wikipedia.
then he became you know Jimmy whale the
scum okay it's a
yeah Jimmy whale is a very big part of
deep state okay I digressed over and uh
okay um so but let's go here okay so
this You are saying homoglyph that that
means similar characters
spam.
So you get go there you can see I
documented them unic code obfusation
masquerade [laughter]
you have masquerade party. Okay so Greek
small letter omega for English Latin
small letter W. Okay. And so you can see
the here these are the actual spam
messages posted to my blogger. I was
using blogger for for a few years. I
killed it. Okay. Because Google scum I
killed it. But anyway, so you can see I
colored you see the red parts are fishy
characters. They are trying you know
they they pretend to be some other
characters. Okay. But they look exactly
the same in many cases. Found that. O is
a you know Greek O and English O they
look exactly the same. Okay so here's
example quite a few quite a lot
actually. So this page page down page
down. So each one of these is comments
okay from spammers on my blog blogger
you see more more more
a lot
uh more. So why are these not uh
colored?
Uh let's see. Oh, okay. Yeah. So now
here's another technique of spam. Please
tell me how beautiful I am. Okay. This
is a ask kissing scam using the
technique of ask kissing. they they post
you know links or whatever's spam to
your blog uh but they are very nice you
know for example hello I've been
following your blog for some time now
and finally got the courage to go ahead
and give you a shout out from Porter
Tech Taxis just wanted to tell you keep
up the excellent work my website
cigarettes online [laughter]
very Nice as kiss ass as kissing
technique.
Hi there to everyone. It's actually a
pleasant for me to go to see this web
page. It includes important information.
My blog view it. Okay. Whatever spam and
scams.
So over you know ever since the uh
beginning of internet 30 40 years ago
you have all these spams and they
so in fact they got worse
and worse you know and the tech geeking
the programming idiots I so much despise
them because they don't know what you
they doing you know they thought this or
that oh we can fight spam by this way
that way made it worse worse and worse
and worse and this opensource fanatics
made It was it now? So it became totally
controlled by deep state and meanwhile
deep state many of these scam situation
they are like intentionally
allowed by deep deep state or even
created by deep state you see by like
for example Google
you know but we shall not you know say
too much about it because
anyway so that's about spam Okay,
so we were talking talking about
homoglyph spam. Okay, so now
copy that
paste that. So that's the index page and
go back here. Copy that.
Paste. So showing browser. So we talked
about
soft software engineering social scams
like agile. Uh did we include yeah the
agile okay
dead because of AI because AI is
extremely you know you can ask any
questions you know um and you get
correct answer
translation SEO spam.
Why Google? Why does Google give SEO
advice? Google crimes index web spam
scam SEO index. Okay. And we did we
include that homoglive.
No. So let's copy that.
Copy.
Paste. Okay. So now we did that. Now
let's continue the comment.
better than evil mod. Yes, absolutely
[laughter]
much better than evil mod. Okay, you
just have to try it. Softly keys. Uh L
is pretty cool. I've only studied
That's also Yeah, that's the most
popular one. for proof proof what
they call proof assistant.
Uh it's basically a programming language
for doing mathematical proofs. Have you
experienced with IBM programming
languages such as Coobo, Forran, RPG?
Nope. Coobo, no FRA. But I have heavy
experience with RPG. Uh and I talked
about it. Search for my website or my
YouTube. search for HP28 calculator or
search my website for eight queens
puzzle because in 1993
I spent $200 something dollars bought
this HP28 calculator and that's using
RGP so I learned how to program that's
actually my first programming language
on the calculator
so I've been recently working with the
codebase on IBMI and it unlike many
other parodym I've worked before. Okay.
So, Coobo is pretty bad. Uh for I don't
know much about Forran. Coobo is so bad.
It's um but it's still used, you know,
in I on IBM mainframe RPG. Do you you
know are you presuming I'm presuming you
mean the like the uh stack based
uh like HP calculator use, right? Or are
you talking about something else? Or are
you talking about fourth? No, I don't
have experience on fourth. Have you ever
been one of these scams? Ever seen to
avoid scam filters? Okay. What? Okay.
So, we digress a lot. Uh, now what we
do? So, there's actually more to
demonstrate. So, here is run for
example. Good morning in run. Good
morning. Okay. Copy that. Copy. go to
Twitter and go here and we continue our
spam
run. This gets the white men excite
excited in particular the Brits
and the German people run. Okay. Uh so
because run is uh basically white man's
historical character set. Uh and okay
then you we got braille. Okay so braille
is designed for the blind but you we can
have fun by
you know we can have like type
characters in braille. Copy. Go here.
Reply. Paste.
Do it. Fantastic.
Amazing. Okay. So, we demonstrated all
these and then what we actually want to
do is create one for the circle
characters. Okay. So, let's see. Showing
browser. We want to create one for the
circle letters that doesn't exter.
So we can copy the square very similar.
Okay. So
okay. So paste that and circled. Let's
see.
Okay. And our second square.
Uh
okay. So
what you want to do there? Yeah. So go
to squared.
Go to it. Copy that.
Search for top. We want to add
the
you see if you scroll down you can see
this topic box. Okay. Convert uh text to
unic code. So we want to add circle
letters here. Okay. So let's add there.
So this is uh unic code. Wait
topic
topic there. Okay. You want to add it
here. So square add it here. Okay. Make
a list. Make a list. Wait. Not talk
show. Uh mistake. So you want the circle
that. So copy that.
Paste. Make a list. Okay, that's what we
want. Then we want to update this
navigation box to all these pages. Okay.
So what we can do is look at the pink
window. You can see the command I call
press press press press. Now it's in all
pages. Now if you refresh refresh you
can see circle letters and you go there
and at the bottom you can see um
this navigation box we added.
Okay. So now you just go steal the code.
So you go to the square page go to the
top then steal the code here. So let's
see.
Yeah. So
yeah. So
cut all the whole block there.
Close it. Now go open the circle page.
Now update today's date.
You see? Press press. It's already
today's date. Okay. Now you just uh go
here. Open. Paste the block here. Paste.
Showing browser. So you got this
that's that's new. Okay. Now you just
change it modify it by saying that uh
convert alphabet to
circle characters. Okay. Now you
shouldn't say convert alphabet. You
should say convert.
Let's just say convert to circle
characters. Make it simple. Okay. Then
you need to change all the
okay then okay you also so here is the
JavaScript for that page you need to
change this of course make a backup and
uh well okay so we copy it so now let's
just say circle
okay now open that copy the hole
Open a new empty. Paste it. Save. Make a
backup. Go to the directory and uh make
the backup to be TS. So we have
TypeScript. You can see TypeScript.
Okay. Now close close.
Open it. Unicose circle characters.
That's right. Okay. Now delete that. So
now we need to work on this page. Now,
now uh so we got a JavaScript going.
Okay, now go back here. So what about
let's change all the word square to
circle. We modify this systematically.
Okay, hold on a second. Let me highlight
all the words circle. I mean all the
words square. Okay, only one occurrence.
Uh okay.
So,
so that's the So, let's see what is
this. Uh so that's just the display.
Okay. So, white and black. Okay. So, you
got also black.
Okay. Then you also got parentheses
version which we should want eventually.
But let's be simple. Let's just uh do
those. Okay. So this change it to
display square by to change to display
CIC. Okay. Do it. Do it. Okay. It just
one occurrence. And now open this
TypeScript. Change. Do it. Okay.
Now the other thing you want to change
is this. Of course. Now make it easy to
read. Wait. So how do you make make it
one line per
you know per space. Uh that doesn't look
good. So you want to make it
uh you see you want to change them to
the circled version. So how do you let's
see okay for the square version they
only have capital. They don't have lower
case. Am I correct?
So the squared version
they don't have lower case but for the
circle version we do. Okay that's
interesting.
Uh yes for the circle version so we
could have okay let's we have to do it
manually. Okay so copy that copy
we just redo this entire block.
Uh,
do I make sense? Do you understand? Do
you understand?
Do you understand? What am I doing?
Wait. Okay. So, this this is a lower
case. Lower case we needs its own home.
Paste it here. Uh, capital case. Press
press to make it one chart per line. And
you need to insert
uh let's do that quotation mark and
comma. Okay. So, and you need to insert
uh what is this? Uh you need to insert
square bracket. Okay.
We can do that. But uh let's
do
you need a square bracket. In fact, you
need
Uh let's do it here like this. Okay. So
you need you need to insert A to Z.
Okay.
So do I have a custom command? Yes.
Casa insert A to Z. There it is. Column
A to Z. So how many? 26 though. There it
is. But incorrect. Undo. So let's let's
try again.
Fantastic. Can you see? Fantastic. Now
Oh god. Okay. Now this is Emacs Mro
Magic. Okay.
Yeah, let's do that. and uh
do that. And now you need square bracket
none. Okay, you see uh actually not
none. You need um
so the command is saw cord lines.
Fantastic magical command. Can you guys
see? Um,
you see that command code lines. So, let
me show you. Co. Now, you want a square
brackets and at the end you want a
comma. There it is. Okay.
Fantastic. And uh, okay. All these are
capital letters. Okay. So, actually can
we now you see this is capital D.
this capital A. Let's see. Uh, let's
magnify. Okay.
Can you press a key and make it lower
case? Let's try. Do it. No, it doesn't
work.
Okay. So, it actually it just work on um
Yeah. Oh, it does work. Jesus.
Fantastic.
Okay. So let me show you guys why why
the excitement excitement. Okay. So you
can see this block they don't agree. You
got lowerase Latin alphabet but you got
capitalase
circle. You want them to agree. Okay.
But can you make them one shot? Yes, you
can. Let's try. Do it. Do it. Do it.
Yeah. Fantastic. You can. So the command
I'm calling
is of course the custom command. Let me
show you. Okay. Is this command toggle
letter case? Okay. And that is
implemented very easily. So um
there okay so but okay it's like 10
lines of code but basically you just
have to call it checks whether the
current work uh letter is lower case or
capital is case. If it's lower case it
changed to capital. If it's capital
change to lower by calling. So there are
three commands you call upase initials
region that's building emac okay or you
can call upase region building emacs or
you can call down case region so my
command actually just a wrapper so it
automatically do them depending on which
I mean so you don't have to like
manually select and think about whether
you want uppase or lower case you know
it just cycles so this command of course
is on the web you can grab for three. In
fact, if you just search for kasar um
toggle letter case, you'll find it. I'm
pretty sure there it is. The kasar
toggle letter case is a custom EMAC list
command designed to overcome the
limitations of standard EMAC case
changing functions.
Fantastic AI, you know, and you can go
to my case direct uh my page directly so
you can see. Okay, so you can grab the
code for you Emacs users.
Is this interesting? Are people still
watching me?
Seven. Not too bad. Okay. say hi or uh
donate to me, PayPal me, go to my
website kasi.info me, donate to me, uh
make some comments, you know, thumb up
my videos, things like that. I truly
despise this, you know, this marketing
little
uh gimmick that because that destroyed
USA. it it you know it's it destroyed
the you know the internet because of
these giant corporations Twitter YouTube
like for example you go to Twitter or
YouTube or or Reddit all the comment is
announced people lost
responsibility especially you zoomers
because you it was designed to make you
that way you know you go to YouTube all
the comments are idiots right you know
that you know that deeply right that's
and that in fact that's how you behave
too because you have to follow that's
the way how things are so you go to the
website you you make a non you you make
idiotic comments nobody know who you are
you cannot make friends you throw away
comments you know post that's what
people these you know young people call
post and memes that's what you
enjoy you idiots
so the entire internet the western by
the way the white men's internet like
UK, Canada, Australia, you know, USA or
controlled by USA of course became that
way because they don't want you. So it
kind of prevent you from having
meaningful com communication
conversation you know it cater it makes
you think that that that's the way
things are you know you don't know
nobody everyone is an you just
you know posting like enjoy
yourself that's your life you you know
enjoy your life just go online post
and babble that's what you guys are
being trained conditioned that
So the entire that's USA you know
YouTube same thing Twitter same thing
Reddit same thing [laughter]
hacker news same thing then then of
course among them you get the fights you
know the social justice warriors the
black lives matter the Christians you
know you make you guys fight them
so it is the collapse of USA
and what can you do almost nothing
basically like uh you know
that's you know so so that's how I feel
and now there's AI well that's another
thing okay so
get back to my topic so I was saying
yeah so if you guys want this command of
course go there showing brows so you can
grab it the code okay now close.
That's toggle letter case. Okay, very
useful. It happens to be close uh for
for us because for example, copy the
whole thing. Uh let's say uh paste it
here. We don't need this anymore. You
see this lower case? We can just delete
it. Now go to the top. Go to the top.
Now select this whole block. You know,
make it one line.
Delete this part. Now call the command.
Actually select it. Okay. Uh select it.
Okay. Make them all capital. All lower
case. All capital. You see all lower
case. Capital lower case. Beautiful. So
one case for capital and then we need
one case for lower case. Okay. So uh
yeah. So let's So this good capital
lower case fantastic and this square Mr.
squares we don't need you anymore cut
and this part we don't need anymore.
Okay so now let's just let me work on
this. Okay so let's you know you don't
know what I'm doing but you will in a
bit. Okay so this is white box letter.
So let's copy that. So that is a array.
You turn a array of pairs of array in
JavaScript. You turn that you feed it to
the map constructor new map that returns
a map data structure uh which in Python
also known as dictionary or hash table.
Okay. Or in Java map. So there are
several names for this data structure.
You can call it dictionary, you can call
it hasht very and you can so dictionary
hasht or you can call it map depending
on the programming language or it is
also known as keyed list
uh you know so but so I was thinking you
know the dictionary
um it's hard to decide which one is
better uh jargon okay because I thought
about this for quite a file
uh so the conclusion is indecisive okay
I can't say which jargon is better but
at one time I thought dictionary is like
um hip you know like the python idiots
you know they don't know computer
science so the gonga
they created dictionary actually but
dictionary is pretty intuitive because
that's what you you know when people
know what dictionary means you know you
have one
and bunch of definition that's like a
hash table, right? But actually
dictionary is a term
it's a old jargon. Okay, so it's it's
not new from Python. It was actually
old.
So hasht is also old jargon. Key list is
actually also old. So so there's no like
the best jargon for this kind of data
structure. Anyway, that's digression.
Okay. So anyway, we got that that we got
this. So the is the syntax correct? I
hope so. Okay, so we got that and then
so that was the white box letters. We
need to change the name. Okay, so this
is a oh this is a set. So we got font
map you got a set white box you got
several items then each set the value is
a is a map. Okay. So now let's go to the
black box letters there. So you can see
we don't need this no more. Okay, create
a new array and this new will be that
cut paste. Fantastic. Okay, now remove
the empty lines. Okay, now just let's uh
rename the white box letters to
up case actually no actually you should
combine these two. Yeah, you don't need
Okay, so you don't funny. So you just
combine the two. Okay.
Yeah. So, is that right? Yeah. You map
them. Uh, yeah. So, you combine the two.
Fantastic. Okay.
And
the black box letters is just empty.
Okay. Like leave it empty. It'll still
work. Right. So,
okay. Now
we are about done. So check uh wait make
sure you don't
wait.
Okay.
Now back up. Now compile it. Compile the
code.
Fantastic success.
Okay. So we got the JavaScript done. Any
more comments? I do agree the western
internet is very chaotic. Yes.
Peer career. Hi. Hi.
Uh RGB3. So I don't know RPG3.
Uh that's reverse polish programming
language, right? That's a reverse polish
lisp. The language on the HP calculator
is called that. Okay. Oh, IBM PRG3. IBM
PRG3 report program generator 3 is a
high level programming language. It's
magnified.
Developed by IBM for business
applications primarily on mid-range
systems like the system 838 and later
AS400
introduced in 17 in 1978. It succeeded
succeeded RPG2. Okay. Report program
generator. No, I don't know this. Uh I
don't know what is this.
So it's not what I was thinking. I was
thinking
reverse polished list. Okay. Uh you have
to say uh program there re you know
reverse polished list programming
language RPL.
So RPL is basically the name for the
HP28 calculator. Okay. So
uh God what? RPL. So you have to say God
programming language. Okay. So
yeah there. So there's a Wikipedia
article on that. Okay. And so this is
effectively my first programming
language I learned and programmed for
about three uh for for actually for 10
years. Well, so beginning in 1993 and
just search for
uh so let me show you this again. So um
search for so let's go to page similar
character spam.
Yes, we talked about that hacker news.
So search HP calculator. Okay, we got HP
uh 35. Oh, that one.
That's okay. That's a a friend.
So, anyway, the one I'm talking about is
this one. Okay. So, I bought this one.
This is mine in 2000 in uh in 1993 for
like $250.
Today is like five probably 500. So so
this is very advanced. Okay. In today's
dollar probably 500. So [snorts] I spend
you know out of my my work at at then
back as a secretary you know like almost
minimum minimum wage you know. So I
spent $250 back then. But this
calculator
that's that's this is the first
it's not the first graphing calculator
because the first graphing calculator is
the Japan's Casio FX3000
I believe if you search you know you'll
find it Wikipedia you'll tell you you
know search for graphing calculator but
this is the first that can solve
symbolic expressions for example the
quad quadratic formula you know solve
any quadratic
poly equation it can solve it
symbolically okay not just numerically
so I learned so so this is you know this
this the programming language is called
RPL okay
I mean the manual doesn't I I I don't
think the manual actually called the
name but anyway so I wrote a lot my
first program is this eight queens
puzzle solution before that's before I
know anything about programming All I
do, all I do is just read the manuals
from cover to cover. Okay? So, I'm an
avid manual reader. I talked about this
many times. Like every I read manuals.
Okay? That's my life. Unix man page.
the the Unix people. The most
idiotic, you know, documentation and
Python. Most idiotic. Okay. So,
basically, but I read I just read
documentation. That's what I do for, you
know, I'm about to my life is not too
much longer you know I I got maybe 10 20
more years okay so but reading
documentation is what I do so I read a
lot so that's how I learned programming
okay so I don't know anything about
I didn't go to school not reading okay I
I well anyway so back to JavaScript back
to Typescript in fact so can we actually
uh does it work close it close it. We
compiled it showing browser. So we go to
the unic code circle letters page.
Can we type? Can we try it? Yes, it
already worked. [laughter]
Fantastic.
Let's see. Good morning. Fantastic and
beautiful. Try now. Try capital letters.
Okay. ABC.
Capital letter didn't work. Why? Because
I know why. Because in So go to the
TypeScript, open it. Somewhere here we
lowered it.
God forbidden. So somewhere here we
lowered it because there it is. Can you
see? So you see we don't want that
because for the square case there's only
one C uh you know there's only capital
case. So,
so now
now now compile the code. Success. Go
back to the page. Refresh.
Fantastic. It you know it works. So
fantastic. So we have done our job
today. Now copy that. Go to Twitter.
Twitter.
Bunch of tweets. you twit.
Good morning. Fantastic and beautiful.
That concludes today's talk show. I
believe I did what I wanted to do and I
hope you guys find this talk show
interesting. We coded JavaScript. So
here is the actual this is a typescript.
Uh and by the way, this I want to
modify. I don't I don't like that. So I
want to change it to delete that part
actually. Um
you see do you guys know what it is? But
let me show you. Okay. But but basically
we are done. So you see what this do is
um
so let's see. So this uh what
okay so you can see this parenthesize
expression you want it to be instead of
like that
uh let me show you okay it's a bit long
so so that this block of code
make a copy I want to change it to
Um
yeah as
change to that. Okay compare that change
to that. So basically what this does
this this part is Typescript. This
basically does a type conversion. it
force force the value of this function
to be HTML input element. Why do you
need one want to do that? Because if you
don't do that then you compile the code
it will say
error
ts2339
property value does not exist on the
type element
which is kind of a kind of idiotic you
know it's kind of the effect of the dome
for some reason they cannot make it you
know not produce error you know it's
trying to say property value does not
exist on the type element Okay. So
anyway, so the solution is to force the
HTML input element. Okay. You don't want
a generic element
for this query selector. No, I don't
understand. I don't know why can they
make
make it automatic, you know, why why
can't this query selector just return um
whatever? I I don't know. So anyway, so
you have to add this syntax in
Typescript just force that element.
Okay, I mean what they call the C and
C++
idiots. What they call cast. Okay, these
imperative idiots. They this what you
know what they typically call this
casting. Okay, type casting. These
they polluted the entire computing
industry with the with their idea of the
casting ship. Okay. Anyway, so back to
Typescript. So you got you need to make
this. Now if you want to do this, there
are two syntax. One is just put this in
front with that angle bracket. The
alternatively
uh for example, let's say uh so one way
is is that uh x. Okay, that's one way.
Alternative is you say
uh
okay that's one way. That's one way.
That's another way. Okay, so you got two
way to do this. But typically when you
add that you know this x is complicated.
You know it's a function call or
whatever. So so usually you end up you
need to put the parn on that and in this
uh same thing. So you know like um
typically so that's why you see this
complicated kind of thing. Okay. So now
but I you know so
before I I I prefer this syntax
but now I prefer this syntax with the S
as keyword because that you have English
word you can actually search you know
for example you can just search for as
to find all all such locations but
otherwise it's it's more harder because
I mean the difference between these two
syntax is that one is syntax based, one
is keyword based. Okay, so this is a bit
digression about programming language
syntax design kind of issues about
syntax design. What what why does this
matter? Because for example, if you are
designing a language first of all,
should you allow do you want your
language to have these aliases? Do you
want or should it be just one way? you
know either do you choose that way or
that way. Just period. Don't give give
people like choices like oh but you can
do it also oh I you can also do it that
way or this way and I prefer that way
and when you read other people's code
they do it that way. Oh but then you
have to read style guide. Style guy says
oh we we we we like this way you should
do it this way. Another corporation
disagree
So I don't I don't know why Typescript
you know if I was Typescript designer I
wouldn't have two like alternative
syntax like you don't want that okay you
don't want these idiotic choices anyway
so but that's the way TypeScript is okay
so anyway so that's why that's why I'm
doing diddling this is called code
diddling because you know like you what
I'm doing is like first first about this
little detail should it Should I make
code look like that or should it looks
like that? [laughter]
Okay. So, delete that. Delete that.
Delete that. Okay. I hope you guys
understand
what I'm saying. Did Do I make sense? Do
I make sense? Like I didn't Did I waste
my time babbling about this? I hope not.
Okay. So, so let me let me just um
kind of do a screenshot here so that um
so the posterity understand
[laughter] they can at least they can
see what I've talked about in this
episode of talk show. Okay, about this
issue of syntax design.
Um well actually we need to comment it.
Okay. Let's be elaborate. Okay.
Okay. So you can Okay. So let's be
elaborate. Let's just spend you know
let's just spend the full time to
comment on this issue syntax design
issues. Okay. So first of all in
Typescript
and I want my um
okay so let's go here in Typescript
you need to you can cast types
to prevent some errors prevent some dome
type errors prevent then some type
errors
from Doom the document object model.
Okay. Uh for example, we did okay. So
for for example
[sighs] uh we're getting too elaborate.
God uh we should close down. So thank
you. Time spent not wasted. Great. Uh
good good night. Uh never waste my time.
Fantastic. Thank you. I agree for
interesting useful stuff. Thank you.
Fantastic. Okay. So, I I that's it for
today, but let me document finish
documenting this. Okay. So, uh yeah. So,
let's just fully write it out. Okay.
Copy that. Delete that. Uh let's go to
talk show. Okay. Let's go to talk show.
Circle letters. We config that today.
Fantastic. Close. Go back to talk show.
What is this? This is talk show. So we
now are talking about some Typescript
details. So in Typescript you can cast
types to prevent some uh type errors
from DOM.
For example uh for example
you get
uh for example you get delete that make
it one line. Make it one line. Comment
this out and
copy comment this out and remove this
that that and try to compile it and you
got that. Okay, close it. For example,
you got that error. So reopen it.
Uh so uh so then what you can do so okay
so so what you can do is add this
Okay.
Or that. Make it code. Make it code.
Make a paragraph.
Make it arrow report. Make it code. Make
it paragraph. Write that. Showing
browser. So it looks beautiful. Scroll
down. So we have the we have documented
what's going on here. Okay. And
now you have syntax design issue.
Should should you have
sugar syntax in your programming
language? Should you?
That's a issue. And
if not, which should you choose? Okay,
that is a question. Showing browser. So
that is what we spent the past 15
minutes talking about the TypeScript
menu detail.
Now the TypeScript happens to allow both
and I don't like it. I like prefer one.
And also the question about which is
better. Okay, that's a and this this
issue happens in every language. So even
though it's kind of trivial but not
really. Okay, this issue
happens in every programming language.
Okay, and you know like you have
alternative syntax. Should you allow
alternative you know syntax so-called
sugar syntax that's from the idiot?
This jargon sugar syntax is from an
idiot. I think his name is Paul
something you know you know you can look
up the history of the jargon sugar
syntax you'll find it anyway but it's
you know so it's a should you do should
should you have it that's one question
of course most most of the time the
purpose of sugar syntax is that it makes
your programming language much more
convenient okay so so there's a criteria
if something is frequently used or is so
make it so much easier to type then you
probably want to have sugar syntax for
that you know so anyway it depends so
should you have sugar syntax if so then
you know whether you know which form or
whatever okay that document that and
that's it for today I think so show in
browser so did we uh yeah we talked
about everything oh one more thing
I was going to do do this this is the
funky unic code. Okay, but let's
uh let's reserve it for next time.
Tune in tomorrow. Okay, something
something like that. So we talked about
so let me show you. Okay. So there.
Okay. So you know unic code go to unic
code search
you'll find it this funky characters. If
you just search for type to get all unic
code characters whose name contain the
type you'll find these uh funky
characters. So they are for example this
one large type piece lower right arc
funky. So they they they they are
designed to form a word like what I'm
not sure exactly what they form. Large
type piece center of Y. So you got X and
Y
Z with crossbar
uh raised upper left arc. So you what
character does that form? So I don't
know exactly what's the purpose of
these. I mean they are to form large
letter letters but what context I don't
know. So anyway, so it's very, you know,
it's quite interesting for as part of
Unicode. So we're going to dive into
that
uh this in some next episode.
Okay, bye guys.
Uh bye guys. I think that's it. Bye.
Bye.
[sighs]
Showing Bowser.
Okay.